Mertz mss., 1902-2019 LMC 2914
Lilly Library
- Subject Files
  - Antiques and Jewelry
    - Catalogs, clippings and periodicals, 1947-2002; 4 Folders (Box 111, Folder 5-8)
  - Arabic
    - "Words and phrases", undated (Box 111, Folder 9)
  - Art
    - Clippings, 1966-1985 (Box 111, Folder 10)
    - IFAR (International Foundation for Art Research) journal, 2000-2002; 2 Folders (Box 111, Folder 11-12)
  - Bronte
    - Periodicals, publications and essays, 1993-1995; 2 Folders (Box 111, Folder 13-14)
  - Burroughs, Edgar Rice
    - "Burroughs Bulletin", 1993-1998 (Box 111, Folder 15)
  - Cats
    - "The Scratch Sheet" - Maine Coon newsletter, 1970-1975 (Box 111, Folder 16)
  - Clothing and Textiles
    - Paper dolls (folders 1-4), undated; 4 Folders (Box 111, Folder 17-20)
    - Paper dolls (folders 5-7), undated; 3 Folders (Box 112, Folder 1-3)
    - Paper dolls (folder 8), undated (Box 193, Folder 20)
    - "Sewing - clothes, quilts", 1962-1983 (Box 112, Folder 4)
    - "Sewing - dolls, toys", 1960-1988 (Box 112, Folder 5)
    - "Knitting, crochet", undated (Box 112, Folder 6)
    - "Needle Arts" magazine, 1976-1977 (Box 112, Folder 7)
    - "Past Patterns" magazine, 1983-1990 (Box 112, Folder 8)
    - "Needlework", 1968-1990; 2 Folders (Box 112, Folder 9-10)
    - "Lace", 1986-1990?; 2 Folders (Box 112, Folder 11-12)
    - Publications and clippings, 1964-2006; 2 Folders (Box 112, Folder 13-14)
    - Reference book with note from Beth Mertz, undated (Box 193, Folder 21)
  - Denmark
    - Travel guides, clippings and publications, 1981-1986?; 3 Folders (Box 112, Folder 15-17)
  - Dunnett, Dorothy
    - "Marzipan and Kisses" - 24, undated (Box 112, Folder 18)
  - Egyptology
    - Coursework and Juvenilia
      - Egyptian History notebooks (folder 1), 1947? (Box 112, Folder 19)
      - Egyptian History notebooks (folder 2), 1947? (Box 113, Folder 1)
      - "Aramaic", undated (Box 113, Folder 2)
      - "Demiotic", undated (Box 113, Folder 3)
      - "Hieratic", undated; 2 Folders (Box 113, Folder 4-5)
      - "Coptic dictionary - my copy", undated (Box 113, Folder 6)
      - "Frankfort - Art of the Ancient Near East", 1948-1949 (Box 113, Folder 7)
      - Hieroglyphs notebook, undated (Box 113, Folder 8)
      - "Textes de la Premiere Periode Intermediaire" by J.J. Clere/J. Vandrier, 1948 (Box 113, Folder 9)
      - "Archaeology of Egypt", undated (Box 113, Folder 10)
      - Notes on Egyptian grammar and hieroglyphs, undated; 3 Folders (Box 113, Folder 11-13)
      - "Notes on journal articles", undated; 2 Folders (Box 113, Folder 14-15)
      - "Ancient Art and the Hittites", undated (Box 113, Folder 16)
      - Miscellaneous textbooks, 1951-1970 (Box 113, Folder 17)
      - Index cards - "Queens", undated; 2 Folders (Box 113, Folder 18-19)
      - Index cards - "General", undated (Box 114, Folder 1)
      - Index cards - "Amarna", undated (Box 114, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous notes and coursework, undated (Box 193, Folder 22)
      - Miscellaneous Egypt index cards in box (Box 196)
    - Newsletters and Periodicals
      - Amarna Research Foundation, 1999-2000 (Box 114, Folder 3)
      - ARCE (American Research Center in Egypt), 1971-1985; 3 Folders (Box 114, Folder 4-6)
      - ARCE - North Texas chapter, 1997-2004 (Box 114, Folder 7)
      - ARCE - Washington, D.C. chapter, 2001-2004 (Box 114, Folder 8)
      - Canadian Mediterranean Institute Bulletin, 1984-1989 (Box 114, Folder 9)
      - Egyptian Archaeology (EES), 1991-2008; 5 Folders (Box 114, Folder 10-14)
      - EES (Egyptian Exploration Society), 1988-1990 (Box 114, Folder 15)
      - Egyptological Newsletter (Brown), 1998-2001 (Box 114, Folder 16)
      - KMT, 1990 (Box 114, Folder 17)
      - KMT, 1991 (Box 114, Folder 18)
      - KMT, 1992 (Box 114, Folder 19)
      - KMT, 1993 (Box 114, Folder 20)
      - KMT, 1994 (Box 115, Folder 1)
      - KMT, 1995 (Box 115, Folder 2)
      - KMT, 1996 (Box 115, Folder 3)
      - KMT, 1997 (Box 115, Folder 4)
      - KMT, 1998 (Box 115, Folder 5)
      - KMT, 1999 (Box 115, Folder 6)
      - KMT, 2002 (Box 115, Folder 7)
      - KMT, 2003 (Box 115, Folder 8)
      - KMT, 2004 (Box 115, Folder 9)
      - KMT, 2005 (Box 115, Folder 10)
      - KMT, 2006 (Box 115, Folder 11)
      - KMT, 2007 (Box 115, Folder 12)
      - KMT, 2008 (Box 115, Folder 13)
      - KMT, 2009 (Box 115, Folder 14)
      - KMT, 2010 (Box 115, Folder 15)
      - KMT, 2011 (Box 115, Folder 16)
      - KMT, 2012 (Box 116, Folder 1)
      - KMT, 2013 (Box 116, Folder 2)
      - KMT Index - Vol 1 thru 12, undated (Box 116, Folder 3)
      - Oriental Institute/Chicago House, 1992-2004; 2 Folders (Box 116, Folder 4-5)
      - Ostracon, 1991-2004; 2 Folders (Box 116, Folder 6-7)
      - The Scroll (Ancient Egypt Studies Association), 2002-2004 (Box 116, Folder 8)
      - Society for the Study of Egyptian Antiquities (SSEA), 1992-2000 (Box 116, Folder 9)
    - "KV5" - clippings, 1995 (Box 116, Folder 10)
    - "KV55" - clippings and correspondence, 2001?; 2 Folders (Box 116, Folder 11-12)
    - KV10/Amenmesse Project - correspondence, publications and articles, 1996-2009; 3 Folders (Box 116, Folder 13-15)
    - "Report of the Northhampton Expedition", undated (Box 116, Folder 16)
    - "Theban Desert Roads", 1994-1997? (Box 116, Folder 17)
    - "Archaeology" - clippings, 1964-1996; 3 Folders (Box 116, Folder 18-20)
    - "Archaeology" - clippings (oversize), 1964-1996 (Box 189)
    - "Zahi on Tut (again)" - clippings and correspondence, 2010 (Box 116, Folder 21)
    - "Age of Royal Mummies" - articles and correspondence, 1982? (Box 116, Folder 22)
    - "Amarna bibliography" - and publications, 1977-1982? (Box 117, Folder 1)
    - "Amarna Royal Tombs Project" - correspondence and publications, 1999-2001 (Box 117, Folder 2)
    - "History of the Sudan" - articles, undated; 2 Folders (Box 117, Folder 3-4)
    - "[Emma] Andrews diary" - article, undated (Box 117, Folder 5)
    - "Brooklyn Museum Gallery Guides" - publications, undated (Box 117, Folder 6)
    - "Queens and Princesses of the Amarna Period" by Lynda Green, 1998; 2 Folders (Box 117, Folder 7-8)
    - Email discussions of articles, 1998-2000; 2 Folders (Box 117, Folder 9-10)
    - Essays/papers, undated (Box 117, Folder 11)
    - "Tombs of the 17th Dynasty at Thebes" - Winlock, undated (Box 117, Folder 12)
    - Clippings, 1972-2000; 2 Folders (Box 117, Folder 13-14)
    - Figure mock-ups, undated (Box 117, Folder 15)
    - Offprints and articles (folders 1-5), 1945-1998; 5 Folders (Box 117, Folder 16-20)
    - Offprints and articles (folders 6-7), 1945-1998; 2 Folders (Box 118, Folder 1-2)
    - Offprints and articles (folders 8-9), 1945-1998; 2 Folders (Box 194, Folders 7-8)
    - Miscellaneous, 1992-2005? (Box 118, Folder 3)
    - Hatshepsut - articles and correspondence, 2007 (Box 193, Folder 23)
    - Maps, travel guides and museum publications (folders 1-5), undated; 5 Folders (Box 193, Folder 24-28)
    - Maps, travel guides and museum publications (folders 6-9), undated; 4 Folders (Box 194, Folder 1-4)
    - Correspondence to/from Mertz, undated (Box 194, Folder 5)
    - Business cards, notes and ephemera, undated (Box 194, Folder 6)
    - "Mistress of the House"/Women in Ancient Egypt - articles, 1992-1996? (Box 194, Folder 9)
    - Oversize maps and plans, 1978-1980? (Box 197)
  - England
    - Travel guides, ephemera and notes, 1965-1972?; 8 Folders (Box 118, Folder 4-11)
  - Fairfax County Archaeological Society
    - Publications, 1989-1996 (Box 118, Folder 12)
  - Fakes and Forgeries
    - Clippings, 1997 (Box 118, Folder 13)
  - Georgette Heyer
    - "The Georgette Heyer Quarterly" - Vol 1 Issue 1, 1979 (Box 118, Folder 14)
  - Germany
    - Travel guides, ephemera and notes (folders 1-5), 1960?; 5 Folders (Box 118, Folder 15-19)
    - Travel guides, ephemera and notes (folders 6-15), 1960?; 10 Folders (Box 119, Folder 1-10)
  - "Ghosts, Crime"
    - Clippings, 1966-1993? (Box 119, Folder 11)
  - Humor
    - Clippings, notes and correspondence, 1985-2006?; 2 Folders (Box 119, Folder 12, Box 193, Folder 19)
  - "Jerome (ghost town in Arizona)"
    - Publications and ephemera, 1971-1979; 2 Folders (Box 119, Folder 13-14)
  - Ladies' Home Journal
    - Issues, 1890-1899 (Ovflat 40)
  - MacLeod, Charlotte
    - Newsletter, 1988-1995? (Box 119, Folder 15)
    - Interviews, 1989-1993 (Box 119, Folder 16)
    - "Booknews from the Poisoned Pen", December 1990 (Box 119, Folder 17)
  - Mystery (genre)
    - "Bouchercon XXIII" program, 1992 (Box 119, Folder 18)
    - "Deadlines" (MWA - Rocky Mountain chapter), 1990-1995? (Box 119, Folder 19)
    - "Murder ad lib", 1989-1995 (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - "Mystery and Detective Monthly" - #36, 1987 (Box 120, Folder 2)
    - MWA directories, 2006-2010 (Box 120, Folder 3)
    - Mystery Scene - No. 3-6 (Box 120, Folder 4)
    - Mystery Scene - No. 7, 8, 9, 11, 12 (Box 120, Folder 5)
    - Mystery Scene - No. 13-17 (Box 120, Folder 6)
    - Mystery Scene - No. 18-21 (Box 120, Folder 7)
    - Mystery Scene - No. 22-23 (Box 120, Folder 8)
    - Mystery Scene - No. 27-28 (Box 120, Folder 9)
    - Mystery Scene - No. 29-30 (Box 120, Folder 10)
    - Mystery Scene - No. 30 (2 copies) (Box 120, Folder 11)
    - Mystery Scene - No. 31-33 (Box 120, Folder 12)
    - Mystery Scene - No. 34-37 (Box 120, Folder 13)
    - Mystery Scene - No. 38-40 (Box 120, Folder 14)
    - Mystery Scene - No. 42-44 (Box 120, Folder 15)
    - Mystery Scene - No. 45-47 (Box 120, Folder 16)
    - Mystery Scene - No. 48, 50-51 (Box 120, Folder 17)
    - Mystery Scene - No. 52-54 (Box 120, Folder 18)
    - Mystery Scene - No. 55-57 (Box 121, Folder 1)
    - Mystery Scene - No. 58, 62 (Box 121, Folder 2)
    - Mystery Scene - No. 63-64, 66 (Box 121, Folder 3)
    - Mystery Scene - No. 67-68 (Box 121, Folder 4)
    - "Red Herrings" (CWA), June 1999 (Box 121, Folder 5)
    - The Third Degree (MWA), 1985-1986? (Box 121, Folder 6)
    - "Murder Manual: A Handbook for Mystery Writers", 1988? (Box 194, Folder 11)
  - Poisons
    - Notebook and research, undated (Box 194, Folder 10)
  - Richard III
    - Periodicals, 1993-1995 (Box 121, Folder 7)
    - Facsimile of George Buck's "Life and Reign of Richard the Third" (Box 188)
  - Rome/Italy
    - Travel correspondence, 1997 (Box 121, Folder 8)
    - Travel guides and publications, undated; 8 Folders (Box 121, Folder 9-16)
  - Victoriana
    - Clippings, 1981-1992 (Box 121, Folder 17)
  - Women
    - Articles and essays, undated (Box 121, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Clippings and articles (folder 1), 1899-1998? (Box 121, Folder 19)
    - Clippings and articles (folder 2), 1899-1998? (Box 121, Folder 20)
    - Travel ephemera, 1966? (Box 122, Folder 1)
- Professional Files
  - ACWL (American Crime Writers League)
    - BULLETin - No. 16-17, 21-23, 26, 28-31, 1990-1993 (Box 122, Folder 2)
    - BULLETin - No. 33-36, 38, 41-44, 1993-1995 (Box 122, Folder 3)
    - BULLETin - No. 45, 47-57, 1995-1997 (Box 122, Folder 4)
    - BULLETin - No. 58-62, 64-71, 1998-2000 (Box 122, Folder 5)
    - Writings by Mertz for BULLETin, undated (Box 122, Folder 6)
    - Committee membership/elections, 1992-1994 (Box 122, Folder 7)
    - Membership forms/inquiries/lists, 1994-1995? (Box 122, Folder 8)
    - Networks with other organizations, 1991-1994 (Box 122, Folder 9)
    - "Publicity guide for ACWL: places to go… or not", 1989-1991 (Box 122, Folder 10)
    - Expenses, 1989-1991 (Box 122, Folder 11)
    - Publicity code, undated (Box 122, Folder 12)
    - Code for conventions, 1992-1993? (Box 122, Folder 13)
    - Royalty statements, 1989-1993; 2 Folders (Box 122, Folder 14-15)
    - Correspondence, 1990-1995; 4 Folders (Box 122, Folder 16-19)
  - ARCE (American Research Center in Egypt)
    - Newsletter, 1994-1998 (Box 122, Folder 20)
    - Board of directors, 1997-1999 (Box 122, Folder 21)
    - Long Range Planning Committee, 1997-1999 (Box 123, Folder 1)
    - Annual Meeting, 1996; 3 Folders (Box 123, Folder 2-4)
    - Annual Meeting, 1997; 3 Folders (Box 123, Folder 5-7)
    - Annual Meeting, 1998 (Box 123, Folder 8)
    - Annual Meeting, 1999; 2 Folders (Box 123, Folder 9-10)
    - Correspondence, 1991-1999; 4 Folders (Box 123, Folder 11-14)
  - Authors Guild
    - Correspondence, 1967-1990; 2 Folders (Box 123, Folder 15-16)
    - Bulletin, 1966-1972; 2 Folders (Box 123, Folder 17-18)
  - Grouchercon
    - Grouchercon, 1995 (Box 123, Folder 19)
    - Grouchercon, 1997 (Box 123, Folder 20)
    - Grouchercon, 1998 (Box 124, Folder 1)
    - Rationals, 1988-1989? (Box 124, Folder 2)
    - Future Grouchercons, 1993-1995?; 2 Folders (Box 124, Folder 3-4)
    - Virgin Gorda, 1996 (Box 124, Folder 5)
    - Grouchercon - Pennsylvania, 1993 (Box 124, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 1993-2000 (Box 124, Folder 7)
  - Malice Domestic
    - Malice I, 1989 (Box 124, Folder 8)
    - Malice II, 1990 (Box 124, Folder 9)
    - Malice III, 1991 (Box 124, Folder 10)
    - Malice IV, 1992 (Box 124, Folder 11)
    - Malice V, 1993 (Box 124, Folder 12)
    - Malice VI, 1994; 2 Folders (Box 124, Folder 13-14)
    - Malice VII, 1995 (Box 124, Folder 15)
    - Malice XV (Lifetime Achievement Award), 2003 (Box 124, Folder 16)
    - Malice 17, 2005 (Box 124, Folder 17)
    - Malice 24, 2011-2012 (Box 124, Folder 18)
    - Malice 30, 2018 (Box 124, Folder 19)
    - Elizabeth Peters Breakfast registration, 1989 (Box 124, Folder 20)
    - Limo receipts, 1989 (Box 124, Folder 21)
    - By-laws, 1992 (Box 124, Folder 22)
    - Trademark registration, 1989 (Box 124, Folder 23)
    - Procedures and operating rules, 1995 (Box 124, Folder 24)
    - Nominees and certificates, 1989-1995 (Box 124, Folder 25)
    - Publicity and reviews, 1992-1994? (Box 124, Folder 26)
    - Anthologies, 1994-1995 (Box 124, Folder 27)
    - Mertz's planning notes, 1994-1995? (Box 124, Folder 28)
    - Malice Domestic incorporation, 1988-1992 (Box 124, Folder 29)
    - Membership and directory, undated (Box 124, Folder 30)
    - Nominating committee, 1995 (Box 125, Folder 1)
    - Minutes, 1994-1995 (Box 125, Folder 2)
    - Form letters, undated (Box 125, Folder 3)
    - Whimsey Award and Foundation, 1992-1995; 2 Folders (Box 125, Folder 4-5)
    - Promotional material, 1992? (Box 125, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous programming notes and material (Box 125, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1989-1995; 3 Folders (Box 125, Folder 8-10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1991 (Box 125, Folder 11)
    - "Usual Suspects" - Vol. 1 No. 1-Vol. 6 No. 1, 1992-1997; 2 Folders (Box 125, Folder 12-13)
    - "Usual Suspects" - "Out of the Past" [Anne Perry article] typescript by Beth Foxwell, undated (Box 125, Folder 14)
    - Programs - Malice I-VII, IX, XVI, 1989-2004; 3 Folders (Box 125, Folder 15-17)
    - Program - Malice XIII, 1994 (Box 192, Folder 22)
    - Agatha Award for Best Nonfiction Work certificate - Charlotte MacLeod, 1994 (Box 192, Folder 23)
    - "Not Everyone's Cup of Tea: an Interesting and Entertaining History of Malice Domestic's first 25 Years" by Verena Rose and Rita Owen - typescript, 2013; 3 Folders (Box 192, Folders 24-26)
  - Mystery Writers of America
    - "Book reviews - Edgars" - notebook, undated (Box 125, Folder 18)
    - Edgars, 1987; 2 Folders (Box 125, Folder 19-20)
    - Committee of Ten/Sisters in Crime, 1986-1987; 2 Folders (Box 125, Folder 21-22)
    - Correspondence ("The Stupid MWA Thing"), 1989-1990 (Box 125, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous, 1982-1992 (Box 125, Folder 24)
    - Best Novel Committee, 1984 (Box 192, Folder 27)
- Writings by Others
  - Barnard, Robert
    - "A Handbook to Edwin Drood" - typescript and correspondence, undated (Box 125, Folder 25)
    - "The Final Chapter", undated (Box 126, Folder 1)
  - Black, Charles
    - "The Waking Passenger", 1990 (Box 126, Folder 2)
    - "Telescopes and Islands", 1990 (Box 126, Folder 3)
    - "Owls Bay in Babylon", 1990 (Box 126, Folder 4)
    - "The Humane Imagination in the Great Society", 1990 (Box 126, Folder 5)
    - "Let Us Rethink our 'Special Relationship' with Israel", 1990 (Box 126, Folder 6)
  - Black, Michael
    - "The Dream Merchant", 2006 (Box 126, Folder 7)
  - Block, Lawrence
    - "My Life In…", 1993 (Box 126, Folder 8)
  - Bond, Carrie Jacobs
    - "The Grub and Stakers House a Haunt", undated; 2 Folders (Box 126, Folder 9-10)
  - Brush, Edwin
    - "Cousin Walt" - correspondence and typescript, 2001 (Box 126, Folder 11)
    - "Unbounded Horizons", undated (Box 126, Folder 12)
    - "The Love Song is Alive and Well", undated (Box 126, Folder 13)
  - Caudwell, Sarah
    - "The Madman's Advocate, 1992 (Box 126, Folder 14)
    - "Malice Among Friends", 1996 (Box 126, Folder 15)
  - Coleman, Shauri
    - "Sense for Dollars" - correspondence and publication, 2005 (Box 126, Folder 16)
  - Conroy, Richard Timothy
    - "Old Ways in the New World", undated; 2 Folders (Box 126, Folder 17-18)
    - "Three Short Stories", undated (Box 126, Folder 19)
  - Dorman, Kathy
    - "Anti-Parenting", 1993 (Box 126, Folder 20)
  - Eiseley, Loren
    - "The Christmas of the Talking Cat", undated (Box 126, Folder 21)
  - Fisher, Sally J.
    - "Writings", 2001 (Box 126, Folder 22)
  - Foxwell, Elizabeth
    - "The Image of Joan of Arc" - title page, 1990 (Box 126, Folder 23)
    - "Unsinkable", 1996 (Box 126, Folder 24)
    - "Victorian Feminist and Swashbuckling Sleuth: Elizabeth Peters' Amelia Peabody Emerson", 1994 (Box 126, Folder 25)
  - Gandy, Karla
    - "Kat Mandu's Holistic Advertising Agency" - correspondence and publication, 2002 (Box 126, Folder 26)
  - Herter, Dick
    - Untitled manuscript, 1992 (Box 126, Folder 27)
  - Kolb, Elene
    - "When Women Finally Got the Word", 1989 (Box 126, Folder 28)
  - Lovesey, Peter
    - "Monologue for Magna", 1996 (Box 126, Folder 29)
  - MacLeod, Charlotte
    - "Balloon Man - original" - annotated typescript, correspondence and floppy disks, 1997; 3 Folders (Box 126, Folder 30-32)
    - "Balloon Man - Mertz's edit" - annotated typescript and floppy disk (folder 1), undated (Box 126, Folder 33)
    - "Balloon Man - Mertz's edit" - annotated typescript and floppy disk (folder 2), undated (Box 127, Folder 1)
    - "Stick with your Woolies", 1967 (Box 127, Folder 2)
  - McCrumb, Sharyn
    - "She Walks These Halls", undated; 2 Folders (Box 127, Folder 3-4)
    - "Nine Lives to Live", undated (Box 127, Folder 5)
  - Meltzer, Edmund S.
    - Course materials, 1987-1988 (Box 127, Folder 6)
    - "The Ancient Egyptian Contribution to Fantastic Literature", 1977 (Box 127, Folder 7)
    - "Agatha Christie and Rex Stout in memoriam", 1977 (Box 127, Folder 8)
    - "Into the Daylight", undated (Box 127, Folder 9)
  - Mertz, Elizabeth
    - "Beyond Symbolic Anthropology", 1985 (Box 127, Folder 10)
    - "Legal Ideology and Linguistic Theory", 1985 (Box 127, Folder 11)
    - "Rule-Centrism versus Legal Creativity", 1985 (Box 127, Folder 12)
    - "A Cape Breton System of Personal Names", 1983 (Box 127, Folder 13)
    - "'Realist' Models of Judicial Decision-Making", 1987 (Box 127, Folder 14)
    - "Science and Relativism", 1987 (Box 127, Folder 15)
    - "Language and Mind", 1982 (Box 127, Folder 16)
    - Publicity, 1988-1993 (Box 127, Folder 17)
  - Mikus, Margaret Dubay
    - "Full Blooming" - CD and correspondence, 2008 (Box 127, Folder 18)
  - Morrison, Cassie
    - "Fragile Fragments of Fantasy" - audiocassette, undated (Box 127, Folder 19)
  - Murray, Lois Anne
    - "Rexford Hall", undated (Box 127, Folder 20)
  - NPR (National Public Radio)
    - "The Prufrock Affair: A Chain Mystery of the Air" - drafts and correspondence, 1988 (Box 192, Folder 4)
  - Pulver, Mary Monica
    - "Father Hugh Investigates", 1992 (Box 127, Folder 21)
  - Read, Michael N.
    - "The Apprentice and the Pyramid" - correspondence and outline, 2004 (Box 127, Folder 22)
    - "Steel Bars and Dirty Concrete", 1998 (Box 127, Folder 23)
  - Ripley, Alexandra
    - Talk for Center for Women, 1999 (Box 127, Folder 24)
    - Publicity, 1991 (Box 127, Folder 25)
    - "Scarlett" - notes and revisions, undated (Box 127, Folder 26)
  - Roth, Ann Macy
    - "Amelia Peabody Emerson: A Living Myth" - typescript, undated (Box 192, Folder 3)
  - Shannon, Beth T.
    - "Sun and Stars" - galleys and correspondence, 2011 (Box 127, Folder 27)
  - Shook, Ken
    - "Solve a Sudoku Puzzle" - correspondence and publication, 2007 (Box 127, Folder 28)
    - "Memoirs" - typescript and correspondence, 2009-2010 (Box 127, Folder 29)
  - Svehla, Susan
    - "Mad About Movies" #4, 2006 (Box 127, Folder 30)
  - Unknown
    - "The End of the Raven by Edgar Allen Poe's cat", 1995? (Box 127, Folder 31)
    - "The Corbett Correspondence", 1995 (Box 127, Folder 32)
  - Whitney, Carol
    - "Thou Shalt Not Profit from Bad Writing", 1995 (Box 127, Folder 33)
  - Fanfiction
    - Baker, Scottie - "Crocodile on the Sandbank" screenplay, 2006 (Box 127, Folder 34)
    - Reigle, Dave - Peabody story, 2004 (Box 127, Folder 35)
    - Menke, Susan - "The Ibis in Flight", undated (Box 127, Folder 36)
    - Author unknown - "Cat Wars" (Star Wars/Peabody crossover), undated (Box 127, Folder 37)
    - Fischer, Stephanie - dream about Nefret and Ramses, 2002 (Box 127, Folder 38)
    - Author unknown - letter from Sherlock Holmes to the Peabodys, undated (Box 127, Folder 39)
  - "Publicity - friends and relatives", 1977-2000; 2 Folders (Box 127, Folder 40-41)
- Personal
  - University of Chicago convocation program, 1950 (Box 127, Folder 42)
  - Design of Mertz's gravestone by Jay Heidel, undated (Box 127, Folder 43)
  - Oak Park - River Forest High School Reunion - Class of '45, 1970 (Box 127, Folder 44)
  - History of Astoria, IL, 1962 (Box 128, Folder 1)
  - Bibliography and publication history, 1985? (Box 128, Folder 2)
  - Oriental Institute Annual Report - memorial to Mertz, 2013 (Box 128, Folder 3)
  - ARCE Bulletin - memorial to Mertz, 2013 (Box 128, Folder 4)
  - KMT - memorial to Mertz, 2013 (Box 128, Folder 5)
  - Business cards - "book people", undated (Box 128, Folder 6)
  - Business cards - "Egyptology", undated (Box 128, Folder 7)
  - Business cards - "Miscellaneous", undated (Box 128, Folder 8)
  - Visa application - Egypt, 1995 (Box 128, Folder 9)
  - Mortgage documents, 1982-2008 (Box 128, Folder 10)
  - Kathryn Gross baby book and photo album, undated (Box 128, Folder 11)
  - "The Fad" - Earl D. Gross's high school yearbook, 1922 (Box 128, Folder 12)
  - Pet paperwork, 1970-1985 (Box 128, Folder 13)
  - Marriage book of Earl Gross and Grace Tragellas, 1924 (Box 128, Folder 14)
  - Birth certificate - Grace Tragellas, 1904 (Box 128, Folder 15)
  - Birth certificate - Earl Gross, 1902 (Box 128, Folder 16)
  - Deeds - Grace Tragellas, 1902-1951 (Box 128, Folder 17)
  - Children's book featuring Mertz's pets, undated (Box 128, Folder 18)
  - Birth certificates - Mertz, 1927 (Box 128, Folder 19)
  - NARAL membership card, undated (Box 128, Folder 20)
  - "Directions" notebook, 1981? (Box 128, Folder 21)
  - "How to Do Things" notebook, undated (Box 128, Folder 22)
  - Stationery, undated (Box 128, Folder 23)
  - Tennessee Squire Association - membership card and certificate, 1992 (Box 128, Folder 24)
  - Bookplates for Mertz's personal library, 2013? (Box 128, Folder 25)
  - Elizabeth Peters-Barbara Michaels scholarship at Hood College, 1990-2001 (Box 128, Folder 26)
  - House - Avignon/Lorien, 1978-1996 (Box 128, Folder 27)
  - Passport, 2010? (Box 128, Folder 28)
  - Antique furniture in Mertz's home, undated (Box 128, Folder 29)
  - Hood College honorary degree, 1990-1991 (Box 128, Folder 30)
  - "Items from Barbara Happy Board in kitchen", undated (Box 128, Folder 31)
  - Scrapbooking stickers and stamps, undated; 2 Folders (Box 128, Folder 32)
  - "Chapel Valley garden work", 1999-2000 (Box 128, Folder 33)
  - Chicago House Bulletin - memorial to Mertz, 2014 (Box 128, Folder 34)